So following the change control process,
not the first time I've discussed this,
that's how important this is.
Let's go into more detail.
So the steps involved
in change control, and
these are yes, on
predictive traditional projects.
So first we have to identify the need for
a change.
Now a change request can be initiated
verbally, but it needs to be documented.
We perform an impact assessment.
How will each change request affect the
budget, schedule, resources, constraints?
How will it affect any and every other
part of our project?
And we'll look for alternatives.
So again, with the alternatives analysis,
we'll do a cost benefit analysis.
The benefits should always outweigh the
cost.
And we submit that change request.
We'll follow the steps outlined in our
change management.
plan to obtain approval or rejection or
possibly deferral.
Let's hold off.
Let's wait.
Let's delay this.
So we'll get approval from the appropriate
authority.
We will update our change
log and communicate the status
of the change request to
all interested stakeholders.
Remember, any stakeholder involved in the
project can submit a change request.
They never forget what they want.
So we will communicate the disposition of
that change request.
And we might have to get their buy-in.
We update all plans and documents
accordingly.
This is a trio.
The approved change request will lead to
plan, might include changing our approach,
strategy, or baselines, and updating any
documents affected.
So that's really important that we do all
of these steps.
We'll implement the approved, change
request in direct and manage the project
work, we will also in control quality,
verify, test the approved change.
Make sure it's actually been
implemented that a change
request for a defect repair has
actually fixed the component.
So now it's conforming.
A little note here.
If there are sellers,
vendors working on the
project, a contract change
control system is used.
We have an extra level of complexity
there.
So approved change
requests will be implemented
in control procurements
only with procurements.
Everything else, the approved
change request will go to
direct and manage the
project work to be implemented.
Exam tips and impact analysis always
involves quantified values.
For example, the defect will take two
weeks to prepare.
We need one additional resources and
impact analysis.
Those are quantified
values versus this defect
is quick and easy or
this is a major change.
That is not an impact assessment.
Okay?
These are all too subjective.
definitely keep that in mind more exam
tips the PM might not be performing the
actual analysis but utilizing SMEs team
members if a question states that the team
has already performed an analysis no
further analysis needs to be performed
keep that in mind all right it is not
always just us we have team members SMEs
working with us so again if they have
already done an impact assessment.
You do not need to do another one.
All right, the authority to approve,
reject, or delay a change request may come
from an outside organization like a
government agency.
For example, making changes
to a building may require
approval, a permit from a
local village or town council.
So something to keep in mind.